<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20151101</CreaDate><CreaTime>16012600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">GEOL_LS_COMPILATION</itemName><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\DNR\DIVISIONS\GER_DATA\gis_editing\projects_current\landslide\url_edit\2014_data\ger_portal_landslides_landforms\ger_portal_landslides_landforms\landslides_and_landforms.gdb</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation><nativeExtBox><westBL Sync="TRUE">638587.375000</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">2489324.750000</eastBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">117569.073730</southBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">1347674.625000</northBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></nativeExtBox><imsContentType>002</imsContentType></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983_HARN</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Foot_US (0.304801)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_HARN_StatePlane_Washington_South_FIPS_4602_Feet</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.0'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;NAD_1983_HARN_StatePlane_Washington_South_FIPS_4602_Feet&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983_HARN&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983_HARN&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Lambert_Conformal_Conic&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,1640416.666666667],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-120.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_1&amp;quot;,45.83333333333334],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_2&amp;quot;,47.33333333333334],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,45.33333333333334],UNIT[&amp;quot;Foot_US&amp;quot;,0.3048006096012192],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;,2927]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-117498300&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-98850300&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;2048&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-200000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;8192&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-2000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;8000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;2&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;2&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.002&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;2927&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef><lineage><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files (x86)\ArcGIS\Desktop10.0\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\ChangePrivileges" Date="20141205" Time="082721">ChangePrivileges 'Database Connections\esri_ropadevl_dc.sde\ROPA.GEOL_LS_COMPILATION' "geol_server_user, ropa_read" GRANT #</Process><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files (x86)\ArcGIS\Desktop10.0\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\ChangePrivileges" Date="20141205" Time="083409">ChangePrivileges 'Database Connections\esri_ropadevl_dc.sde\ROPA.GEOL_LS_COMPILATION' djes490 GRANT GRANT</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.0\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\CalculateField" Date="20141208" Time="140755">CalculateField ROPA.GEOL_LS_COMPILATION LANDSLIDE_ID [OBJECTID] VB #</Process><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files (x86)\ArcGIS\Desktop10.0\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\ChangePrivileges" Date="20141216" Time="100924">ChangePrivileges 'Database Connections\esri_ropa.sde\ROPA.GEOL_LS_COMPILATION' "GEOL_SERVER_USER , ROPA_READ" GRANT #</Process></lineage></DataProperties><SyncDate>20141204</SyncDate><SyncTime>12102900</SyncTime><ModDate>20141204</ModDate><ModTime>12102900</ModTime></Esri><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdContact><rpOrgName>Washington State Department of Natural Resources, Division of Geology and Earth Resources</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>360-902-1450</voiceNum><faxNum>360-902-1785</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>PO Box 47007</delPoint><city>Olympia</city><adminArea>Washington</adminArea><postCode>98504-7007</postCode><eMailAdd>geology@dnr.wa.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></mdContact><mdDateSt>20141120</mdDateSt><mdStanName>ArcGIS Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer>1.0</mdStanVer><distInfo><distributor><distorCont><rpOrgName>Division of Geology and Earth Resources, Washington State Department of Natural Resources</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>360-902-1450</voiceNum><faxNum>360-902-1785</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>PO Box 47007</delPoint><city>Olympia</city><adminArea>WA</adminArea><postCode>98504-7007</postCode><eMailAdd>geology@dnr.wa.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="005"/></role></distorCont><distorOrdPrc><resFees>None</resFees><planAvDtTm>2014-01-01</planAvDtTm><ordInstr>Available for download from: http://www.dnr.wa.gov/ResearchScience/Topics/GeosciencesData/Pages/gis_data.aspx</ordInstr></distorOrdPrc><distorFormat><formatName>ESRI geodatabase feature class</formatName><fileDecmTech>no compression applied</fileDecmTech></distorFormat></distributor><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">File Geodatabase Feature Class</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>landslide_compilation</resTitle><resEd>version 4.0</resEd><citRespParty><rpOrgName>Washington State Department of Natural Resources, Division of Geology and Earth Resources</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty><rpOrgName>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>Olympia, Washington</delPoint></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>vector digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm></idCitation><idAbs>These data contain polygons defining the extent and characteristics of mapped landslides in the State of Washington. This dataset is a compilation of pre-existing landslide databases from several sources, including the Washington Divisions of Geology and Earth Resources and Forest Practices, and other federal and private compilers. As such, the mapped landslides were originally created to meet a variety of purposes. It also includes more recent landslides mapped by the Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources. This compilation does not include all landslides that may exist in Washington State.</idAbs><idPurp>The Department of Natural Resources, Geology and Earth Resources Division (DGER), also known as the Washington Geological Survey, actively identify, assess, and map landslide hazards using modern geotechnical and geophysical methods. Our hazard maps are critical for land-use and emergency-management planning, disaster response, and building-code amendments. As our population grows, there is increasing pressure to develop in hazardous areas, thus delineating these areas is imperative. In response to the Growth Management Act's mandate to use the 'best available science', our geologists meet with local governments and citizens in at-risk communities to educate about geologic hazards and ensure these hazards are taken into account while planning for growth-management and disasters. The DGER is also a first responder to natural disasters; helping staff the State Emergency Operations Center at Camp Murray and documenting damage in the field. Washington is also prone to landslides triggered by intense rainfall or earthquakes. According to Washington State legislative mandate RCW 43.92. ". . . the geological survey must conduct and maintain an assessment of seismic, landslide, and tsunami hazards in Washington. This assessment must include the identification and mapping of volcanic, seismic, landslide, and tsunami hazards, an estimation of potential consequences, and the likelihood of occurrence. The maintenance of this assessment must include technical assistance to state and local government agencies on the proper interpretation and application of the results of this assessment." DGER has designed and is implementing a GIS-based, statewide landslide database.</idPurp><idStatus><ProgCd value="007"/></idStatus><idPoC><rpOrgName>Washington State Department of Natural Resources, Division of Geology and Earth Resources</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>360-902-1450</voiceNum><faxNum>360-902-1785</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>PO Box 47007</delPoint><city>Olympia</city><adminArea>WA</adminArea><postCode>98504-7007</postCode><eMailAdd>geology@dnr.wa.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></idPoC><resMaint><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="001"/></maintFreq></resMaint><placeKeys><keyword>USA</keyword><keyword>Washington State</keyword><thesaName><resTitle>USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) http://geonames.usgs.gov/</resTitle></thesaName></placeKeys><themeKeys><keyword>lateral spreading</keyword><keyword>landslides</keyword><keyword>mass wasting</keyword><keyword>geologic hazards</keyword><keyword>slumps</keyword><keyword>shallow landslide</keyword><keyword>block slides</keyword><keyword>deep seated landslide</keyword><keyword>debris avalanche</keyword><keyword>soil creep</keyword><keyword>slides</keyword><keyword>rock falls</keyword><thesaName><resTitle>Jackson, Julia A. (ed.), Mehl, James P., Jr. (ed.), Neuendorf, Klaus K. E. (ed.), 2005, Glossary of Geology; 5th ed.: American Geological Institute, 779 p.</resTitle></thesaName></themeKeys><searchKeys><keyword>lateral spreading</keyword><keyword>landslides</keyword><keyword>mass wasting</keyword><keyword>geologic hazards</keyword><keyword>USA</keyword><keyword>slumps</keyword><keyword>shallow landslide</keyword><keyword>block slides</keyword><keyword>deep seated landslide</keyword><keyword>debris avalanche</keyword><keyword>soil creep</keyword><keyword>Washington State</keyword><keyword>slides</keyword><keyword>rock falls</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><LegConsts><useLimit>This digital data and metadata, (hereinafter collectively referred to as the "information"), are provided on an "AS IS", "AS AVAILABLE" and "WITH ALL FAULTS" basis. Neither Department of Natural Resources nor any of its officials and employees makes any warranty of any kind for this information, express or implied, including but not limited to any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose, nor shall the distribution of this information constitute any warranty. The information is collected from various sources and will change over time without notice. DNR and its officials and employees assume no responsibility or legal liability for the accuracy, completeness, reliability, timeliness, or usefulness of any of the information provided nor do they represent that the use of any of the information will not infringe privately owned rights. The information is not intended to constitute advice nor is it to be used as a substitute for specific advice from a licensed professional. You should not act (or refrain from acting) based upon the information without independently verifying the information and, as necessary, obtaining professional advice regarding your particular facts and circumstances. References to any specific commercial product, process, and service by trade name, trademark, or manufacturer do not constitute or imply endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by DNR and its officials and employees. In no event will dnr be liable to you or any third party for any damages arising out of the use of or inability to use the digital data, even if dnr is advised of the possibility of such damages.</useLimit></LegConsts></resConst><resConst><Consts><useLimit>The Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources (DGER) shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. This product is provided 'as is' without warranty of any kind, either expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular use. The Washington State Department of Natural Resources and the authors of this product will not be liable to the user of this product for any activity involving the product with respect to the following: (a) lost profits, lost savings, or any other consequential damages; (b) the fitness of the product for a particular purpose; or (c) use of the product or results obtained from use of the product. Although these data have been processed successfully on computers of DGER, no warranty, expressed or implied, is made by DGER regarding the use of these data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty.</useLimit></Consts></resConst><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001"/></spatRpType><dataLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></dataLang><envirDesc>Microsoft Windows Vista Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3000</envirDesc><dataExt><exDesc>publication date</exDesc><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp/></TempExtent></tempEle><geoEle/></dataExt><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox><westBL>-124.668111</westBL><eastBL>-116.967191</eastBL><southBL>45.587549</southBL><northBL>49.02765</northBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode><westBL Sync="TRUE">-124.668111</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-116.967191</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">49.027650</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">45.587549</southBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt></dataIdInfo><mdConst><Consts><useLimit>The Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources (DGER) shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. This product is provided 'as is' without warranty of any kind, either expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular use. The Washington State Department of Natural Resources and the authors of this product will not be liable to the user of this product for any activity involving the product with respect to the following: (a) lost profits, lost savings, or any other consequential damages; (b) the fitness of the product for a particular purpose; or (c) use of the product or results obtained from use of the product. Although these data have been processed successfully on computers of DGER, no warranty, expressed or implied, is made by DGER regarding the use of these data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty.</useLimit></Consts></mdConst><dqInfo><dqScope><scpLvl><ScopeCd value="005"/></scpLvl></dqScope><report type="DQConcConsis"><measDesc>Each source database was checked for attribute completeness and correct spatial reference before inclusion in this compilation. Some of the source databases do not contain all of the attributes of this compilation, these attributes were left blank as appropriate.</measDesc></report><report type="DQCompOm"><measDesc>Each source database in this compilation studied a specific area or areas within Washington State. As a result this compilation covers the cumulative areas of these studies, not the entire state. Please refer to the extent footprints layer in this geodatabase to see where landslide studies have, or have not, been conducted.</measDesc></report><report type="DQQuanAttAcc"><measDesc>Attribute accuracy varies considerably between source databases. This is a result of the different business needs for which the various databases were made, the scale of the mapping, and the resolution and type of base map or aerial photography used to locate the landslides. Please refer to the Data Confidence field for additional information about a particular source database or particular features.</measDesc></report><report type="DQAbsExtPosAcc" dimension="horizontal"><measDesc>Horizontal accuracy varies considerably between source databases. This is a result of the different business needs for which the various databases were made, the scale of the mapping, and the resolution and type of base map or aerial photography used to locate the landslides. Please refer to the Location Confidence field for additional information about a particular source database or particular features.</measDesc></report><dataLineage><prcStep><stepDesc>As relevant landslide databases are identified/created we merge features from that database into our landslide compilation database. The spatial reference will be changed (if needed) to match the DGER standard projection (WA stateplane south zone, HARN). Fields in the compilation database are calculated from corresponding fields in the new database. Reference fields in the compilation database are then calculated from information about the new database. Landslide Hazard Zonation Data: Landslide processes were modified from the Washington State Department of Natural Resources, Forest Practices Division, Landslide Hazard Zonation Project Protocol. The changes reflect gaps in the LHZ protocol, such as the additions of hyperconcentrated flows and lateral spreads, which are critical in future land-use planning. Landslide processes were grouped into two categories, shallow landslides and deep-seated landslides. Shallow landslides are differentiated to shallow undifferentiated (including shallow colluvial), debris flow, debris slide (which includes debris avalanches), hyperconcentrated flows, block falls and topples. Deep-seated landslides are differentiated to lateral spreads, general deep-seated, earthflows, translational, rotational, composite and megalandslides/sturzstroms. Landslide attributes were modified from the Washington Department of Natural Resources, Forest Practices Division, Landslide Hazard Zonation Project Protocol. Attributes were created for multiple reasons. The first was to establish a balance between critical information and excessive attribution. The second was to ensure critical information would be available for land-use planning and hazard assessment, as well as for future research into landslide hazards. The third was to establish a basis by which to flag landslides that have caused or potentially could cause damage. Emphasis was placed on landslide triggers, such as slope, gradient, and structure. Version History Version 4.0 (November, 2014): Several changes to the schema were implemented to improve clarity and add hyperlinks (where available). Metadata was updated. Version 3.0 (June, 2010): This dataset was migrated from a shapefile to a geodatabase. Feature class names and attribute names were changed, and metadata for the entire dataset was updated. Version 2.0 (April, 2009) Attributes were updated. Version 1.0 (October, 2008) Original data in shapefile format.</stepDesc></prcStep></dataLineage></dqInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><geometObjs Name="GEOL_LS_COMPILATION"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">52809</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></TopoLevCd></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><eainfo><detailed Name="GEOL_LS_COMPILATION"><enttyp><enttypl>landslide_compilation</enttypl><enttypd>This feature class contains landslide polygons and descriptive data.</enttypd><enttypds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</enttypds><enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">52809</enttypc></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>SOURCE_INFORMATION</attrlabl><attrdef>Additional information about the database or feature.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Source Information</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">500</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>GEOLOGIC_UNIT_LABEL</attrlabl><attrdef>Geologic unit of landslide origin.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Geologic Unit Label</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">15</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">LANDSLIDE_ID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Landslide ID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>FEATURE_SOURCE</attrlabl><attrdef>Name of the source database from which the landslide feature was obtained.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Feature Source</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">60</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LAND_USE</attrlabl><attrdef>Description of the land use where the landslide occurred.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Land Use</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">30</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>COMMENTS</attrlabl><attrdef>General comments related to the landslide.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><begdatea>20070817</begdatea><enddatea>20080708</enddatea><attalias Sync="TRUE">Comments</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">255</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>DATA_CONFIDENCE</attrlabl><attrdef>The level of confidence DGER geologists have in the source data.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>Moderate</edomv><edomvd>Medium-scale field mapping; may exclude some landslides due to size or landslide type; remote assessment using several different sources from different scales; most data collected by remote review; captures a subset of landslide in the area</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>Low</edomv><edomvd>Reconnaissance landslide mapping; significant landslide population may be excluded or missing</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>High</edomv><edomvd>Field mapping complimented with high-resolution remote data such as lidar and (or) &gt;1 ft resolution aerial imagery; adjacent landslides may not have been identified or mapped</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>Moderate-High</edomv><edomvd>Systematic landslide mapping following a documented methodology; most landslide information collected by remote interpretation using several sources at various scales; interpretation primarily by remote assessment; captures a subset of landslides in the area</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>Low-Moderate</edomv><edomvd>Small-scale field mapping; may exclude some landslides due to size or landslide type; captures a subset of landslides in the area</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Data Confidence</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LOCATION_CONFIDENCE</attrlabl><attrdef>The level of confidence DGER geologists have in the feature location.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>High</edomv><edomvd>Landslide locations at the time of mapping is accurate and was likely located in the field using GPS and high-resolution remote data such as lidar and (or) &gt;1 ft resolution aerial imagery</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>Low-Moderate</edomv><edomvd>Small-scale field mapping may mislocate landslide perimeter or location as much as several hundred feet; remote mapping may include low-quality imagery or elevation models for landslide interpretation</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>Low</edomv><edomvd>Reconnaissance landslide mapping; landslide perimeter and location may be mislocated exceeding several hundred feet and on occasion thousands of feet</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>Moderate_high</edomv><edomvd>Large-scale field mapping may mislocate landslide perimeter or location as much as one hundred feet</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>Moderate</edomv><edomvd>Medium-scale field mapping may mislocate landslide perimeter or location in excess of hundreds of feet; remote mapping may include moderate-to-high resolution imagery or elevation models for landslide interpretation and follow systematic mapping protocol</edomvd><edomvds>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Location Confidence</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Length</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LANDSLIDE_TRIGGER_EVENT</attrlabl><attrdef>Description of the kind of regional event that has caused the landslide.</attrdef><attrdefs>Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Landslide Trigger Event</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LANDSLIDE_LIMIT_DATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Approximate date of when landslide was first identified --9999 is unknown.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Dates that are specific to each feature.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Landslide Limit Date</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Date</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LANDSLIDE_TYPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Description of landslide types.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attrdomv><udom>Dates that are specific to each feature.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Landslide Type</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">30</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LANDSLIDE_CERTAINTY</attrlabl><attrdef>Likelihood of the existence of the landslide.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Landslide Certainty</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">15</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LANDSLIDE_NAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Name given to the landslide.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Landslide Name</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>SLOPE_MORPHOLOGY</attrlabl><attrdef>Description of the slope morphology</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual description</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Slope Morphology</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Feature geometry</udom></attrdomv><begdatea>20070817</begdatea><enddatea>20080708</enddatea><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>INFRASTRUCTURE_DAMAGE</attrlabl><attrdef>Description of infrastructure damage caused by the landslide.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Infrastructure Damage</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">90</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>STRUCTURE_ASSOCIATION</attrlabl><attrdef>Description of the structure of the landslide</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual description</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Structure Association</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>SOURCE_DB_FEATURE_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>Landslide ID used in source database</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>value field</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Source DB Feature ID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>ASPECT</attrlabl><attrdef>Aspect of landslide.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>value field</udom></attrdomv><begdatea>20070817</begdatea><enddatea>20080708</enddatea><attalias Sync="TRUE">Aspect</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">SmallInteger</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LANDSLIDE_DATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Year/month/day of landslide failure</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Dates that are specific to each feature.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Landslide Date</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Date</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>GRADIENT_DEGREES</attrlabl><attrdef>Numerical cardinal degrees (9999 is unknown.)</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>value field</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Gradient (degrees)</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">SmallInteger</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Area</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>GRADIENT_METHOD</attrlabl><attrdef>How the landslide gradient was determined.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual description</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Gradient Method</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OBJECTID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>DSLS_MORPHOLOGY</attrlabl><attrdef>Textual description deep-seated landslide morphology</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">DSLS Morphology</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">30</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>FIELD_CHECK</attrlabl><attrdef>Description of whether the landslide has been field-checked by a landslide professional.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Field Check</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>URL</attrlabl><attrdef>Hyperlink to on line information about the source database.</attrdef><attrdefs>Washington Division of Geology and Earth Resources</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>textual descriptions</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Hyperlink</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">255</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed></eainfo><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="2927" Sync="TRUE" value="2927"></identCode><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">7.4.1</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spdoinfo><ptvctinf><esriterm><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom code="4" Sync="TRUE"></efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">52809</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo></metadata>
